<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-02T16:35:55+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Family on the go</title><subtitle>Reflections on motherhood, parenting, babies and travel</subtitle><author><name>Coloma Farre</name><email>coloma.farre@gmail.com</email><uri>https://github.com/colomafarre</uri></author><entry><title type="html">Ramona turned 4*</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramona-turns-4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ramona turned 4*" /><published>2019-05-31T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-05-31T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramona-turns-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramona-turns-4/">&lt;p&gt;On May 29th 2019, Ramona turned 4. Four times around the sun! And this year she did it in Nepal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_1813.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_1813.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a very especial birthday this year because I feel like it really was the first one she really understood, anticipated (we made a calendar to count down the days till her day!) and was asking for specific gifts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_2173.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_2173.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since living in Nepal means we see goats and chickens everyday, Ramona has gotten used to sharing more time with animals and knowing more about them, and she really has become an &lt;strong&gt;animal lover&lt;/strong&gt; (at least, much more than beofre!!). She was asking for a baby goat for the longest time, so we decided &lt;strong&gt;that that would be her birthday gift&lt;/strong&gt;! Eventough we have to leave soon back to Spain, we thought it was a good idea to experience the responabilities and fun that comes from taking care of a baby goat (and its mama!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, on her birthday we made french toast for breakfast and we lite a candle so she could ask for a wish, and as we predicted, &lt;strong&gt;she asked for a baby goat!!&lt;/strong&gt; Then, Joe went outside and brought the baby goat we bought for her inside. You should have seen her face of sorprise and excitement! She said, “how did she know!?!?!”. It was very sweet to see her so happy! She named her “Cleta” and her mother “Neta”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4312.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4312.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you have asked, &lt;strong&gt;what are we going to do with the goat once we move back!?&lt;/strong&gt; And no, we are not taking her to Spain (altoght I think Ramona would love that…). We are going to give them to our neighbors. The goats sleep in our neighbors shed now, and that was the deal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4341.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4341.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the afternoon we invited everyone we know to &lt;strong&gt;Ramona’s Birthday Party!&lt;/strong&gt; From 4 pm we were outside in our yard, friends and neighbors came over, we played with ballons, made bubbles, dance to some fun music and had some snacks (bananas and peanuts for everyone). Galileo was the dancing star! He sorprised everyone with the best dancing moves (go see the video at the end of the post!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4186.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4186.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ramona had the best time!&lt;/strong&gt; You could see her enjoying herself, sweating and dancing, singning and laughing, and that was the best! To see her so happy, just filled my heart with joy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4187.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4187.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4188.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4188.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Wearing the same crown I made for her on her first birthday (with changeble numbers and ajustable size)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4237.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4237.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4244.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4244.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4251.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4251.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 7 pm we served dinner: Vegie momos, fried chicken, carrots and cucumbers and prawn chips for everyone! Thanks to Suman, the best cook in Pyuthan, for cooking all of that! And then it was time for cake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4330.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4330.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not having an oven at home meant that we had to order a cake. Ramona asked for a chocolate and strawberry cake. And it needed to be big because we had so many friends coming over! So, it turned out to be the biggest, fanciest cake they ever made in Pyuthan, apparently! Everybody loved it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4263.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4263.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it came time to blow at the candles on the cake, she got really quiet and she waited a long time. Then she said “since I already have a baby goat I don’t know what to wish for”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then she waited some more. Then she said &lt;strong&gt;“I wish for my mom and dad to always be happy”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4265.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4265.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really. She said that. It was so sweet. Sweetest girl ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4273.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/turned4/IMG_4273.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;strong&gt;the video I make every birthday to summerize her year&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this year, she went twice to the US and once to Canada, she started school in Santa Coloma, she went to Berlin to meet her cousins Arthur and Lucy, she spent a very cozy and catalan Christmas, and then we moved to Nepal and travelled to Thailand!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New countries, new places, new friends and new adventures, but same Ramona: smart, curious, sweet, funny and brave. We love you baby girl, we will always love you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">On May 29th 2019, Ramona turned 4. Four times around the sun! And this year she did it in Nepal!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Watching the wheat harvest</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/harvest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Watching the wheat harvest" /><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/harvest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/harvest/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/20190411_091210.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/20190411_091210.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s harvest time in Pyuthan&lt;/strong&gt;. The wheat and barley fields are filled with young workers, mostly women, manually chopping down stalks of grain with sickles under the hot sun. Children carry the cut wheat on their back from the field to their homes. They lay it out to dry. Then the elderly, sitting in the shade, beat the grains of wheat from the stalks by hand. After the fields are harvested, the men plough them with oxen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard, physical work. And from a purely economic perspective, it’s inefficient. Dozens of people do over the course of weeks what a tractor and harvester can do in a matter of minutes. This inefficiency explains, in part, why &lt;strong&gt;the average Nepali worker makes in 20 years what the average American worker makes in one year&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_1657.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_1657.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when you’re here, watching the harvest, &lt;strong&gt;you see more than just the numbers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_1677.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_1677.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see families, living together and working together, with a common purpose. You see ritual and routine, lifestyles intimately tied to the seasons and bound by the weather. You see humans using their bodies, keeping them strong. You see a sense of purpose among the old, whose role is essential to the harvest. And you see the same sense of purpose among the young, who are empowered with the responsibility of helping their family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_2481.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_2481.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/20190423_085546.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/20190423_085546.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve made a point of trying to “get up close” to Pyuthan’s grain harvest. We watch the farmers and we talk to them. We see how they work together. We see how they sweat under the hot pre-monsoon sun. We watch how they wash their sweat-soaked clothes in the river in the evening. We notice how the fields in the valley get harvested first, before the fields higher up in the hills. We observe the schedules (work starts at sunrise, with a break for lentils around 10, and goes into the evening).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/20190411_095530.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/20190411_095530.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the closer we are to the harvest itself, the less the numbers seem to matter. Whereas spending 10 hours hunched over chopping wheat stalks with a sickle would most often be described as “back-breakingly hard” by the average westerner, what we’ve observed is best described by another word: joy. Little boys laughing as their father falls off an oxe plough. A baby napping on her mother’s back as she chops barley. An old lady, sitting barefoot by her grand-daugther, as the two of them stack hay for animal feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_1832.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_1832.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re aware of the numbers. We’re aware that living in dire poverty means that one bad harvest is the difference between malnutrition and starvation. We’re aware that 60% of the children in our area are stunted from not getting enough food. We’re aware that Nepalis live 15 years less than Spaniards on average. We’re aware that there is a fine (and frequently crossed) line between children participating in the household economy and exploitative child labor. There are some things that have to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_1667.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/IMG_1667.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But does everything have to change?&lt;/strong&gt; Must a place like Nepal take the well-worn “development” path - through childhood obesity, cultural homogenization, environmental contamination, elder loneliness and family splintering - in order to avoid the curses of poverty? Can we eliminate the worst of economic deprivation without also eliminating the best of traditional life? And can the rich world learn a few things from the poor world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more time we spend in developing countries, the more doubts we have about the concept of “development” itself. Our contradictions accumulate, and our perspectives splinter. We’ve seen real misery and suffering in Nepal, but we’ve also seen it in the suburbs and poor neighborhoods of the US and Catalonia. The more we see of the world, the less emboldened we are to venture opinions on the way things &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be. Our opinions, formerly so black and white, have taken on a grey-ish hue. &lt;strong&gt;Life, we’ve learned, is complicated&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/20190411_095609.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/20190411_095609.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/harvest/20190419_171402.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/harvest/20190419_171402.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to see more of the harvesting process, check out the video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DKpOSEriQF4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Joe Brew</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tashi Waldorf School in Kathmandu</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tashi-waldorf-school/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tashi Waldorf School in Kathmandu" /><published>2019-04-18T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-04-18T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tashi-waldorf-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tashi-waldorf-school/">&lt;p&gt;Before moving to Nepal I remember googling “Waldorf School Nepal” to find out if there were Waldorf school options for us there! Living in rural Nepal doesn’t give us the opportunity to attend a Waldorf school. But while I was in Kathmandu I had the oportunity to visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://childrenofnepal.org/navigation/tashi-waldorf-school-nav&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Tashi Waldorf School”&lt;/a&gt; and I want to tell you about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1248.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1248.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contacted them and they quickly welcomed us to visit their school. Ramona and I spent one morning with them an we both really enjoyed it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1250.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1250.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1251.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1251.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tashi in Tibetan means &lt;strong&gt;“all that is good”&lt;/strong&gt;. In 2000 Tashi Waldorf School was stablished by two Waldorf teachers. &lt;strong&gt;They started with 5 children from the government orphanage&lt;/strong&gt;. They were looking for donations from all over the world to be able to help more and more children in need. They targeted underprivileged children that couldn’t afford going to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1261.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1261.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays they have a nursery, two kindergartens and classes from one to four. There are 55 children studying in the school, 11 teachers, 3 kitchen stuff, 1 guard and 1 office administrator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1252.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1252.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1258.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1258.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1262.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1262.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1263.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1263.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1312.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1312.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main building holds class 1, class 4, nursery, two offices and a library. In the grounds are classrooms for class 2 and 3, a caretakers building, a traditional Nepali house and a kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On April 25th 2014 &lt;strong&gt;an earthquake, marked 7.8 on the Richter scale, devastated Nepal&lt;/strong&gt;. Many buildings collapsed or were damaged beyond repair. Many of their students lost their homes and now live in tents in temporary camps. &lt;strong&gt;The foundations of the Tashi Waldorf School house were largely affected&lt;/strong&gt; and, after an extensive survey, the building was sadly been deemed unsafe. In response, the community worked hard to build two temporary kindergartens in the outside space and the school management brought forward the long term plan to move the school to a tranquile and calm piece of land on the greener outskirts of Kathmandu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;without funds to invest&lt;/strong&gt; in a new location, the children and teachers of classes 1 to 4 have no option but to &lt;strong&gt;continue lessons in their condemned building&lt;/strong&gt;. They hope that their strict earthquake drill procedures will suffice until enough support is raised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1313.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1313.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1315.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1315.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The Library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1316.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1316.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1319.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1319.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1320.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1320.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1266.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1266.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The Playground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1267.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1267.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1269.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1269.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1273.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1273.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1278.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1278.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1280.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1280.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1282.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1282.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1287.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1287.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1292.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1292.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The kitchen could use some fixing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1293.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1293.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1294.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1294.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
And the bathrooms too…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1296.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1296.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1298.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1298.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1300.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1300.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The teachers make all the pretty toys by hand!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1303.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1303.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1302.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1302.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1304.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1304.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1305.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1305.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1306.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1306.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1307.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1307.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
They really are doing an amazing job, offering such beautiful and empowering education with so little resources. They are given the freedom to play, discover, and develop naturally without pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1324.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1324.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though culturally diverse, &lt;strong&gt;the majority of the children attending Tashi Waldorf School come from disadvantaged homes&lt;/strong&gt;. Their parents work as carpet weavers, construction labourers, and in other manual jobs. Many of the families have migrated from rural areas in search of a better life. Employment opportunities are scarce for those possessing little to no training or skills, and families are forced to live on the margins of society in poor conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1330.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1330.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tashi Waldorf School uses a curriculum which &lt;strong&gt;integrates the principles of Waldorf (Rudolf Steiner) education with the culture and traditions of the Himalayan region&lt;/strong&gt; to create an educational experience that is meaningful and relevant for the children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1333.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1333.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each day the children receive a multivitamin supplement, nutritious snack and lunch, as well as medical, dental and vision care and clothing if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1337.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1337.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1341.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1341.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOW CAN YOU HELP?!?!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to help Tashi Waldorf School and its students you can make a donation. &lt;strong&gt;Any amount would be gratefully received&lt;/strong&gt;! You can donate through &lt;a href=&quot;http://rsfsocialfinance.org/donate-now/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this webside&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;“Children of Nepal”&lt;/strong&gt;, the organization that runs the school. You just need to specify the amount you want to donate and that you have not received goods or services for this donation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the money they would be able to hire a school bus, redo the bathrooms and fix the kitchen. They also need money to sponcership students coming from families in need. &lt;strong&gt;You can help a nepali kid have a better and brighter future!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading and for helping to the extent possible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1342.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/tashiwaldorf/IMG_1342.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">Before moving to Nepal I remember googling “Waldorf School Nepal” to find out if there were Waldorf school options for us there! Living in rural Nepal doesn’t give us the opportunity to attend a Waldorf school. But while I was in Kathmandu I had the oportunity to visit “Tashi Waldorf School” and I want to tell you about it!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2 weeks in Thailand with 2 kids</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thailand/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2 weeks in Thailand with 2 kids" /><published>2019-04-08T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-04-08T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thailand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thailand/">&lt;p&gt;Mid March we travelled from Kathmandu to Bangkok to spend 2 weeks in Thailand as an &lt;strong&gt;improvised family vacation&lt;/strong&gt;! For visa reasons we needed to get out of Nepal (to later have some more time in the country) and we decided Thailand was a good option because it had a direct (only 3 hour) flight from Kathmandu, no too expensive and we were excited about swimming in its beautiful beaches!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a wonderful &lt;strong&gt;vacation full of sweat, salt, water, mangos and pad thai&lt;/strong&gt;!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what we did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:43:06.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:43:06.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first spent 3 nights in Bangkok to discover a little bit the big city, do some shopping and get a first taste of the new country!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:46:17.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:46:17.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a city full of street food stands, lots of markets and temples, colorful tuk-tuks and tourists! We took it very easy because it was so hot and the kids were not used to it, especially the first day! It felt like summer in Florida, humid and sticky! We were so glad our hotel room had AC and we could take breaks and nap during the day! We stayed at the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shantilodge.com/page/guest-house-in-bangkok&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Shanti Lodge”&lt;/a&gt;, a family-oriented guest house&lt;/strong&gt; and really enjoyed our stay! It had a little play area next to the restaurant, delicious food options, from homemade granola for breakfast to delicious pad thai dinner, cocktails and desserts. The family room was simple but perfect for us! If you are looking for a quality budget acomodation you should check them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:47:53.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:47:53.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One morning we took a boat taxi, we visited the &lt;strong&gt;Buddhist riversite temple “Wat Arun”&lt;/strong&gt;, we had some coconut water, crossed the river with another boat to a market, had lunch and walked around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:53:41.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:53:41.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:53:56.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-09:53:56.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:13:03.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:13:03.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:23:15.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:23:15.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:28:17.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:28:17.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:37:53.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:37:53.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I had to rent this skirt because you are not allowed to go in the temple wearing shorts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:39:00.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:39:00.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:39:27.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:39:27.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:45:53.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:45:53.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; The face of a hot baby!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:54:59.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-10:54:59.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A much needed ice cream break!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-11:33:43.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-11:33:43.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-12:45:54.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-12:45:54.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One afternoon we went to the &lt;strong&gt;Changchui Creative Market&lt;/strong&gt;, the most well-known “creative space” in Thailand. It consists of event spaces, art galleries, restaurants, cafes, bars, antique stores and spaces for street music and shows! It was fun to walk around discovering different art pieces! The kids had a great time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-16:52:06.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:14-16:52:06.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 3 days in Bangkok we took a &lt;strong&gt;domestic flight to Phuket&lt;/strong&gt;, this mountainous island in the Andaman Sea. We had a reservation in the Hotel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smileresidence-phuket.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Smile Residence&lt;/a&gt; for 3 nights but we only ended up staying 2 nights. The hotel was great, with a very nice big room, a great pool and a very (very) basic breakfast. But the location was not so great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_1736.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_1736.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_1761.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_1761.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:16-13:09:35.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:16-13:09:35.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rented a motorcycle (to ride as a family like the locals do) and it was fun but very scary with the traffic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:16-18:12:22.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:16-18:12:22.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that we didn’t have more reservations, the idea was to go with the flow and leave some days open of our trip to be able do decide, once there, what we wanted to do. &lt;strong&gt;We decided to go to Phi Phi Islands&lt;/strong&gt;. We made a reservation for one night and went! We found it difficult to reserve for longer without really knowing the place and we wanted to be free to change plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:17-13:40:20.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:17-13:40:20.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We took a speed boat from Phuket city to Phi Phi Island&lt;/strong&gt;, which took about 45 min. The island was amazing!! No cars, just pedestrian streets, beautiful beaches, a lot of restaurants and yes, party bars too, but it didn’t bother us. We stayed a first night at the PP Nice Beach Resort. It was right in front of a little quiet gorgeous beach, 10 minute walk from the center of town. The family room was nice but the AC didn’t work really well and they didn’t have a pool. Ramona was really loving swimming at the pool so we decided to look for another hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:17-17:54:20.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:17-17:54:20.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found &lt;a href=&quot;http://jjresidence.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;JJ Residence Hotel&lt;/a&gt; to be a good fit for us. The room was nice and we had direct acces to the pool from our balcony, which was great and fun! The balcony was also a good hang-out spot for the kids, to play with water out of the sun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:18-09:38:22.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:18-09:38:22.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:23-14:10:51.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:23-14:10:51.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We loved the island so much that we ended up staying all week!&lt;/strong&gt; Galileo got a little sick half way through our trip (with a bd cold) so we didn’t want to travel more until he got better. Also, travelling days are not that fun and mostly exhausting… &lt;strong&gt;So instead of seeing more islands we decided to enjoy the one we were at&lt;/strong&gt; and really discover it’s natural beauty! We had a nice and relaxed week of swimming, eating thai food, drinking fruit shakes to help with the heat, trying different thai desserts, eating a lot of mangos, enjoying the sunsets from the beach and night swimming! It was quite perfect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:23-10:42:07.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:23-10:42:07.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:30:47.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:30:47.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of afternoons we rented a boat to go to different beaches (that’s the only way you can reach some of the most beautiful beaches of the island, by boat!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:46:14.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:46:14.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really loved &lt;strong&gt;“Nui Bay” beach&lt;/strong&gt;. It was the perfect little beach, with white sand, very few people, black rocks and palm trees around, where you can enjoy the most beautiful sunset!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:48:28.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:48:28.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:50:45.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:50:45.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:50:51.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-17:50:51.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-18:00:19.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-18:00:19.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-18:14:05.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-18:14:05.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-18:26:21.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:19-18:26:21.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We spent our days like this&lt;/strong&gt;: wake up, go out for breakfast around the corner to our favorite bakery/breakfast place (the pros of staying a long time in one place is that you get to know the people and start having favorite spots, and we really like that!), Joe would work for a while, while me and the kids would go swim, either to the pool or to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:21-09:52:02.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:21-09:52:02.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-11:35:53.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-11:35:53.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 12 we would have lunch. A few days it was just me and Ramona (because Galileo was extra tired feeling sick and needed more sleep than food…, and Joe was catching up on work), going out for lunch! It was so especial to have some time one on one with her, talking about everything and sharing good food together! I will always remember those lunch dates with my almost 4 year old daughter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:22-13:15:21.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:22-13:15:21.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-12:54:18.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-12:54:18.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Mango sticky rice, a classic Thai dessert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-11:45:35.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-11:45:35.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-11:52:04.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-11:52:04.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After nap we would grab a snack and go together to discover a different beach every afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-17:19:30.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-17:19:30.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Long Beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-17:21:44.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:20-17:21:44.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2380.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2380.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2424.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2424.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Loa Ba Kao Beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2436.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2436.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2511.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2511.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2632.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2632.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After swimming all afternoon we had dinner out! There were so many restaurants! Our favorites were the ones right next to the ocean!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2665.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2665.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week it was time to hit back. We decided to travel back to Bangkok (Phi Phi to Phuket and then to Bangkok) all in one day. This time we took the ferry back to Phuket, which took longer than the speed boat (about 2 hours) but it was cheaper and also much nicer, with AC and room to walk around, which helps travelling with kids!! Then we flew to Bangkok and this time we found a hotel close to the airport so we were not wasting time on the comute the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:24-10:50:25.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:24-10:50:25.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2699.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/IMG_2699.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Pizza on the hotel room floor after a long day of travelling and a quick swim in the hotel’s pool!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:25-12:05:19.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:25-12:05:19.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a hotel close to the airport, we really enjoyed our stay at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.asiasboutiquehomestays.com/en-us&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Asias Boutique Club&lt;/a&gt;. The room was great, had a big pool and it felt very homey and personal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:25-12:28:15.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:25-12:28:15.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:26-09:01:05.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:26-09:01:05.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was our vacation! We didn’t see all of Thailand, we didn’t visit the most important temples in Bangkok, we didn’t go to all the beautiful islands the country has! But we did enjoy our time together in a very different country and will always have great memories of those 2 weeks and all the delicious mangos we ate! &lt;strong&gt;That’s why we travel!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:26-11:17:57.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/thailand/2019:03:26-11:17:57.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the video!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Jft0mR7g-0k&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">Mid March we travelled from Kathmandu to Bangkok to spend 2 weeks in Thailand as an improvised family vacation! For visa reasons we needed to get out of Nepal (to later have some more time in the country) and we decided Thailand was a good option because it had a direct (only 3 hour) flight from Kathmandu, no too expensive and we were excited about swimming in its beautiful beaches!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Homeschooling Ramona in Nepal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/homeschooling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homeschooling Ramona in Nepal" /><published>2019-02-21T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-02-21T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/homeschooling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/homeschooling/">&lt;p&gt;Before we moved to Nepal, Ramona was attending school. The public school of my hometown. She had 11 classmates and a wonderful teacher. She was happy there and we are glad that she was able to do a full a semester of school before we moved to Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we are in Nepal, we thought about sending her to school but the language would be too much of an obstacle (for the moment)… So we decided that &lt;strong&gt;homeschooling her for the time we live here was the best solution&lt;/strong&gt;! She is still very young (3 and a half years old) and I am actually an Early Childhood teacher with 6 years of experience, so teaching doesn’t come new to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_091152.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_091152.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really excited before we moved about this oportunity! Getting materials ready, supplies, ideas, etc. She was too! This past summer I taught an afternoon class in my hometown, where she attended too, and she called it &lt;strong&gt;“Mama school”&lt;/strong&gt;, so that is what we call it now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_144347.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_144347.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we have settled in our new place, we have started “Mama school”, even though she was asking from day one to start school!! We needed a routine, to unpack our bags and settle a little bit and now we are on it! Monday to Friday: Mama School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is our daily rhythm&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wake up (around 7:30), cook and eat breakfast together, Joe goes to work (or starts working from home), I get the kids clean and dressed for the day. We have been playing “hairdresser” as an excuse to do Ramona’s hair in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, around 9, we start with &lt;strong&gt;Circle Time&lt;/strong&gt;. Me and Ramona stand one in front of one another, while Galileo plays around, and we sing some songs and finger play songs together. We always start with the same song, and then I have a list of the ones we know already and the ones I want to teach her, mixing English and Catalan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opening song&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Good morning dear Earth, good morning dear Sun,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good morning dear rocks, and flowers every one,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good morning dear beasts, and birds in the trees,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good morning to you, and good morning to me.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_095528.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_095528.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, we go potty, put our shoes on, drink some water and get ready for our &lt;strong&gt;Morning Walk&lt;/strong&gt;. This has been so far the most enjoyable thing for me (and the kids like it too). Galileo goes in the carrier, on my back, and Ramona walks. Every day &lt;strong&gt;we pick a goal for our walk&lt;/strong&gt;. Sometimes it is to find some flowers for Suman, some rocks to do a craft later, we bring the magnifying glass and look for small things, or we just decide a destination (the big river, the house with the swing, …) and enjoy everything we find on the way. We spend between 45 min and 1 hour wondering around. It has been really nice to walk out of the house first thing in the morning, to be out in nature, seeing the animals, discovering our neighborhood!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_151403.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_151403.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190215_100842.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190215_100842.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_101238.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_101238.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190218_093624.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190218_093624.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we hit back home, Suman is normally there already, getting lunch or laundry ready. We have a &lt;strong&gt;snack&lt;/strong&gt;. Then Galileo may take a nap (he is in the period between needing 1 or 2 naps, depending on how early he woke up that morning) or hang out with her, while me and Ramona work on &lt;strong&gt;the activity of the day&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mondays: &lt;strong&gt;Watercolor painting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tuesdays: &lt;strong&gt;Beeswax modelling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wednsdays: &lt;strong&gt;Coloring with block crayons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thursdays: &lt;strong&gt;Crafting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fridays: &lt;strong&gt;Free day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set the activity out in the porch (we don’t have a table, but the porch steps are working fine for now …), we sing the activity song and we do it together. For exemple, while she paints I paint, which is so nice to have the excuse to paint watercolors again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190212_115939.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190212_115939.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_113306.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_113306.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_103905.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_103905.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These may take more or less time, depending on how into it Ramona is in the moment. Sometimes we have time to do another activity after that (from the ones in the following “extra activities” list) or just some &lt;strong&gt;free play time&lt;/strong&gt; before lunch is ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra activities&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dance class&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Study Nepali&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoga class&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holiday crafts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treasure hunt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finger knitting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flower pressing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleaning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_101950.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_101950.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_110446.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_110446.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190218_103648.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190218_103648.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We eat &lt;strong&gt;lunch&lt;/strong&gt; around 12, out in the porch, looking at the people walk by and talking about when I was a kid (Ramona is very into stories about when we were little kids latlely, and loves asking so many questions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_115105.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_115105.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it is &lt;strong&gt;story time&lt;/strong&gt; (either me or Joe with Ramona in her room) and &lt;strong&gt;nap time&lt;/strong&gt;. She will not always nap, most days yes, other days she will do quiet time, playing with her dolls and reading books until I tell her is time to get out of the room (after about 1 hour).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Galileo didn’t take a morning nap he will go down after lunch too, if not a little bit later for his second nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_165304.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_165304.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After nap we have a &lt;strong&gt;snack&lt;/strong&gt; and go out in our front yard for &lt;strong&gt;outdoor free play&lt;/strong&gt;. We hang the hammock, they play in the sand, build sand-casltes with sticks, etc. Normally the neighbor kids join in on the fun too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Joe is done with work, around 6 pm, I start getting dinner ready, we eat together, then bathe (every other day now…), pj’s, teeth, nurse to sleep for Galileo and stories for Ramona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After writting all this I realized that &lt;strong&gt;we spend most of the day outside&lt;/strong&gt; and I love it! The temperature is great right now to be outside most of the time without being too hot or too cold, which is so nice. This rhythm may change and will get reajusted with time for sure, but for now that is what works for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have organized our homeschooling days thinking about Ramona’s needs and &lt;strong&gt;following the Waldorf philosophy&lt;/strong&gt;, inspired by the time I worked at Morning Meadow Waldorf Preeschool and Kindergarten, and with the help of the awesome seasonal guides by  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wholefamilyrhythms.com/product/full-year-guide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Whole Family Rhythms&lt;/a&gt;. Even though we don’t have everything we would like here (no oven to bake bread, no good watercolor paper, etc) we do what we can with what we have! And I feel like it is working! Ramona is learning so much just being outside, observing nature, asking so many questions and creating and imagining her own little world! It is fantastic and I am so happy to be able to walk with her through this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does this sound to you? Would you like to homeschool your kids? What other activities should we add to our list?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">Before we moved to Nepal, Ramona was attending school. The public school of my hometown. She had 11 classmates and a wonderful teacher. She was happy there and we are glad that she was able to do a full a semester of school before we moved to Nepal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life update from Pyuthan, Nepal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nepal-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life update from Pyuthan, Nepal" /><published>2019-02-18T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-02-18T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nepal-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nepal-update/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_123107.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_123107.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello from rural Nepal! We’ve spent &lt;strong&gt;a little over a month in this country already&lt;/strong&gt;! I can’t belive it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8929.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8929.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8898.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8898.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It has been a kind of crazy month for us&lt;/strong&gt;! When we arrived we spent a few days in Kathmandu, a few days in Pokhara, then a week in Pyuthan (here) but staying at the hotel while looking for a house, and then back to Kathmandu for almost 2 weeks! Last week we finally settled in our new home (what we call “&lt;strong&gt;home sweet home&lt;/strong&gt;”) in the town of Bijuwar, in Pyuthan district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_20190211_125349.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_20190211_125349.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really like our new place, especially the location. It is a little bit far from the “downtown” area (15 min walk) but it is so peaceful and quiet! &lt;strong&gt;Our street is a dirt road where no cars go by&lt;/strong&gt;, a few motorcicles and sometimes you’ll see a tractor, but mostly just people walking. The neighbors have goats, cows, and chickens, there’s a field full of yellow flowers in front of our house, a little creek in the back and 3 minutes down the road we get to the main river, Ramona’s new favorite spot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_103246.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_103246.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_103343.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_103343.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She really likes to play close to the water creeks, pretending she is fishing, following the little paths next to the water, jumping and climbing around. Galileo loves crawling in our front yard, playing with sticks and getting dirty from head to toe! It is really nice to &lt;strong&gt;be able to be in nature just stepping out of the house&lt;/strong&gt;! And our favorite hang out spot: our porch. We spend so much time on it, we even have lunch out there too. And the hammock on it is the favorite of all the neighborhood kids!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190211_150717.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190211_150717.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About our house&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s a 3 bedroom house, with a very basic kitchen (sink and portable gas stove, table and 4 plastic chairs), and bathroom with a faucet (without hot water) for taking bucket baths, toilet (which we installed. Before there was only a squat toilet), and sink. There’s a rooftop where we hang our clothes to dry. It is very simple but very nice by local standards!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical houses here are made out of mud and wood, with little windows and low ceilings. People wash clothes and dishes outside. They even wash their teeth and hair outside! Homes are basically to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190218_100743.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190218_100743.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t have a heating system (nobody does). So what that means is that at night is pretty cold (we have thick blankets and pj’s) and in the morning too, but during the day, luckily, it gets warmer already, so we try to open the windows when it is nice outside so the warm air comes in the house, and basicly &lt;strong&gt;just dress acording to the temperature&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not having hot water is also quite the experience&lt;/strong&gt;. We warm up water with a big kettle for bucket baths for the kids, and we (the adults) take showers during the day when the air is not so cold! I wash my hair seperatly, with my clothes on, which I’ve learned it is better for me, less painful! Joe times his baths to be right after exercise, when his body temperature is hightest. Washing dishes with cold water when it is cold it is pretty unpleasant too…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best thing is&lt;/strong&gt;, we have Suman, a woman that comes every morning, from Monday to Friday, to help us with the kids, with translation, with going to the market, around the house, everything. She is wonderful!! She cooks us delicious lunch, she likes to play with the kids, washes clothes (by hand!!), and is basically our hero here! She knows where to find stuff, she is a mom herself, she anticipates our needs and in general, she and her husband have been very helpful for our family to quickly feel like home in our new house!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190215_124406.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190215_124406.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not having a supermarket to go grocery shopping&lt;/strong&gt;, just little stores with what it feels to us like random stuff, it makes it hard to find what we need. A lot of people have asked about differences on the food here so here is the sum up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fruits and vegetables are everywhere but not a huge variety.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fruits in Pyuthan: oranges (delicios but full of seeds), bananas, red apples, grapes and coconuts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In other areas you can find more variety. Like Kathmandu had avocaDos, kiwis, pineapple, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vegetables in Pyuthan: cabbage, coliflower, broccoli, green beans, green peppers, potatoes, tomatoes, red onions, garlic and sometimes I find zuchinni and eggplants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8918.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8918.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fruits and vegetables taste and look the same.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They eat eggs, chicken and buffalo but a lot of people are vegetarian.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They cook a lot of beans (a lot of different kinds of lentils, black beans, chickpeas, …)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They use a lot of spices and food coloring in their food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They eat dal bhat (rice and lentil soup) &lt;strong&gt;everyday&lt;/strong&gt;, for breakfast and dinner. For lunch they eat some kind of fried stuff like samosas, momos (dumplings), etc. filled with vegetables, chicken, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190206_121700.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190206_121700.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rice is the main food, I would say! And they generaly eat it with their hands!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We can’t find much refrigerated stuff here… We don’t have a fridge either! So, really missing cheese!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can get milk, but it’s not pasteurized (so you have to boil it).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We couldn’t find a coffee maker so instant coffee will do for now (with powdered milk!). They drink more tea than coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190213_121519.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190213_121519.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we have been eating rice everyday too! Thankfully, both Ramona and Galileo like dal bhat already, which makes it easier around here! And I have to say, for being a go-to food, it is pretty nutritious and healty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190217_174818.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190217_174818.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somebody asked about &lt;strong&gt;the most challenging thing so far&lt;/strong&gt;. I would say the first days here in Pyuthan were the hardest. We were staying at a hotel, all packed in a room, with no hot water either, sharing one towel, discovering still the sorroundings, etc. The kids where not used to the spiciness of the food yet, the cold nights in the hotel room, and having to get dressed in the cold morning room too, Ramona missed Santa Coloma a lot, etc… &lt;strong&gt;Transitional periods&lt;/strong&gt;, when you still don’t have a proper place to put your stuff and a kitchen to prepare your own snacks, &lt;strong&gt;are the hardest I think&lt;/strong&gt;. Now we kind of have a routine, our stuff is more or less in place (we still have to buy some furniture) and we feel settled which helps with everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_1160.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_1160.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The easiest thing so far, which I dind’t anticipated&lt;/strong&gt;, was actually the food. I thought I (personaly) wouldn’t like it as much as I like it already! It is spicy sometimes, but just the amount of spiciness I can tolerate, kind of! And in general it is very tasty and yummy (altough very repeptitive, I have to say!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190211_084949.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190211_084949.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will share more about our day to day soon (I feel like there is so much to say,but I don’t want the post to be too long!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;strong&gt;a video of our Saturday morning&lt;/strong&gt; last weekend, when we when down to the river and to eat lunch to our favorite restaurant in town!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a9F1S4SlnZU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading us!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galileo turned 1*</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/galileo-turns-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galileo turned 1*" /><published>2019-01-26T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-01-26T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/galileo-turns-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/galileo-turns-1/">&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;January 21st, 2019 Galileo turned 1&lt;/strong&gt;. One year being a family of 4, of Ramona being a big sister! It may have not been the day I imagined for his first birthday, but it sure was special!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/20190121_161026.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/20190121_161026.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day before we travelled from Pokhara to Pyuthan, which was a &lt;strong&gt;9 hour car ride&lt;/strong&gt; through crazy windy roads with both kids and all our stuff, and an amazing driver that drove us safely to Jumri (Pyuthan district), Nepal! The day went as good as it could go but it still was exhausting! The next day I woke up with a bad cold and I had to be in bed most of the day. But Joe, Ramona and Galileo went on some walks to explore our new home town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8258.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8258.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People when they see us here they are mesmerized! They stop what they are doing and stair at us! We are the first white poeple in town for a long time, apparently! &lt;strong&gt;Everybody wants to hold Galileo&lt;/strong&gt; and take selfies with him, and he seems to not mind it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8328.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8328.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, before sunset, we decided to &lt;strong&gt;throw a little party&lt;/strong&gt; for Galileo! We grabbed a plate, we put some cookies and cut out oranges, we stuck a candle (that I got in Pokhara beforehand) in one of the oranges, asked for some matches at the hotel, grabbed the 3 ballons I had in my bag (I always carry ballons with me while travelling, great entertainment in aerports, etc.) and went out to find a good spot for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_20190121_165930.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_20190121_165930.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had &lt;strong&gt;the crown&lt;/strong&gt; I made for Ramona’s birthdays (see Ramona’s first Birthday party &lt;a href=&quot;http://familyonthego.life/ramona-turns-1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) with the number one for Galileo! He didn’t want to wear it much but there are still some pictures with him wearing it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8268.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8268.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sang the song for him and Ramona helped him blow the candle, which surprisingly kept re-lighting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8297.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8297.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He enjoyed his cookies and oranges!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8286.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8286.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the time to do that there were a lot of people around us, especially women and kids, that had stopped and enjoyed the celebration with us! We shared chocolate and cookies with them, the kids played with the ballons, they passed Galileo around and we had a nice time together. Even if we couldn’t talk much, everybody was happy and it was really sweet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8278.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8278.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8270.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8270.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8321.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8321.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8302.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8302.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is &lt;strong&gt;the video&lt;/strong&gt; of the first year of Galileo in this world, with him looking so tiny at the beggining, a lot of love form her sister, a lot of laughing and travelling around the world! Lucky you Galileo, you have a family that loves you SO much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ltl6yHxpQ88&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">On January 21st, 2019 Galileo turned 1. One year being a family of 4, of Ramona being a big sister! It may have not been the day I imagined for his first birthday, but it sure was special!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First week in Nepal - Kathmandu and Pokhara</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/first-week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First week in Nepal - Kathmandu and Pokhara" /><published>2019-01-25T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-01-25T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/first-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/first-week/">&lt;p&gt;On January 13th 2019 my dad, Ramona, Galileo and I flew from Barcelona to Doha and then to Kathmandu, where Joe was waiting for us at the airport. After a night of little sleep (at least for the adults) we got to Nepal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:01:20.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:01:20.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:25:28.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:25:28.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flying with &lt;strong&gt;Qatar Airways&lt;/strong&gt; was great! Very helpful flight attendants, spacious seats, with the option of having the baby bassinet for Galileo (that he used for a while, even if he almost didn’t fit!), and the flight was not full so we had a couple extra seats for us! So we flew as comfortable as it gets for being in economy class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:35:33.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:35:33.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got to Kathmandu, after dealing with all the visa and paper stuff we took a taxi to the hotel. We stayed at the &lt;strong&gt;Taleju Boutique Hotel in the Thamel neighborhood&lt;/strong&gt; for 3 nights. It was nice to have a patio where the kids could run/crawl around, especially after seeing how busy the city can be!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-09:54:54.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-09:54:54.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent those tree days &lt;strong&gt;exploring the city, at a family friendly pace&lt;/strong&gt;! We walked a lot, bought some souvenirs for my dad to take back to the family, we visited some Buddhist and Hindu temples and in general, we tried to get a feel for the country and its culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:33:24.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:33:24.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The city of Kathmadu is really busy and felt chaotic&lt;/strong&gt;! There’s a lot of traffic, very narrow streets and no sidewalks for pedestrians (in most areas), so it felt a little overwhelming with the little ones. In general, it was a lot to take in for the first days in a new country! You know how it is, when you don’t have enough eyes to look at everything that’s happening around you!? Ramona was a little bit confused the first days. She would observe everything and ask you things like “Why do they have that red spot on their forehead?” or “Why do they where sandals if it’s cold?” She notices everything and I feel like the first days where hard for her (I guess for all of us!!), but it is also amazing how quickly we can adapt!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:43:49.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:43:49.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:44:10.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:44:10.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:49:06.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:49:06.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-08:21:44.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-08:21:44.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-09:20:04.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-09:20:04.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the most intense experiences we had&lt;/strong&gt; was when we visited the Shree Pashupatinath Temple, during a Hindu festival. We paid a guide so he could tell is a litlle bit about what was happening, because that’s one thing we quickly realized, how little we know about their traditions and how different the cultures can be!. We saw a lot of monkeys running around and eating bananas and oranges. Apparently they are protected, just like cows, and feeding them gives the person good karma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:06:02.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:06:02.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;strong&gt;the most breathtaking thing&lt;/strong&gt; was seeing the cremation of a dead body, right next to the river, and the ceremony that that involved, while an festival was happening at the same time, on the other side of the river, with music and dancing and all!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:11:20.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:11:20.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:35:11.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:35:11.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have never guessed that I would see a body burning right in front of me, and I have to say, it was quite unsettling, but after some time and seeing how they experience it, I think it was a very cultural and human way to get to know them better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-10:46:35.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-10:46:35.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Yummy roasted corn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-10:47:48.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-10:47:48.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; So much love!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-11:07:59.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-11:07:59.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Trying to take a family picture!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-15:47:40.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-15:47:40.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; He made us these catalan patches for our bags!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-09:02:02.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-09:02:02.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-09:05:04.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-09:05:04.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forth day &lt;strong&gt;we took a flight to Pokhara&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:02:19.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:02:19.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the smallest plane I’ve ever been on! There were 18 passangers total! It was quite the experience, but actually more pleasant than what I anticipated! It was such a short flight (about 20 min) with beautiful views of the Himalayas. So, no complaints!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:02:46.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:02:46.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:06:00.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:06:00.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pokhara is a beautiful city next to this big lake, sorounded by mountains! It is very touristy, because it’s known as a gateway to the Annapurna Circuit. But there’s much less polution than Kathmandu, and it is a little bit more organized because it’s a newer city. We stayed at the &lt;strong&gt;Vardan Resort N’ Apartment&lt;/strong&gt;. It was very nice with the kids too because we had a little porch and some grassy area for them to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the highlights of Pokhara:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-12:09:11.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-12:09:11.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sailing around the lake!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-12:15:46.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-12:15:46.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pokhara “Disneyland” Funpark! A little bit scketchy but pretty entertaining!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-13:08:24.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-13:08:24.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roasted corn. I Already loved corn but seeing Ramona starting to love it is even better than eating it myself!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-13:33:13.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-13:33:13.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The beautiful views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-16:45:02.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-16:45:02.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And for sure, the craziest thing was &lt;strong&gt;Paragliding with my dad&lt;/strong&gt;!!! (see more in the video below!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-12:58:59.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-12:58:59.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We did some hiking, with our new friends (and baby) we made at the hotel!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-13:53:25.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-13:53:25.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-14:06:05.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-14:06:05.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-14:27:55.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-14:27:55.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-15:07:21.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-15:07:21.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was a great discovery! Getting out of the big city, getting to see some more of the country, it was a good decision to go to Pokhara for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:19-11:17:59.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:19-11:17:59.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that my dad when back to Catalonia and we continued our journey to western Nepal. But I’ll tell you more about that in another post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;strong&gt;a video of my dad’s visit&lt;/strong&gt;, during this first days of the whole family together discovering Nepal! I hope you like it! And maybe get excited to come visit too!?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tMOL1stzQfQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NAMASTE !!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">On January 13th 2019 my dad, Ramona, Galileo and I flew from Barcelona to Doha and then to Kathmandu, where Joe was waiting for us at the airport. After a night of little sleep (at least for the adults) we got to Nepal!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Next destination -&amp;gt; Nepal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nepal-next/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Next destination -&gt; Nepal" /><published>2019-01-11T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-01-11T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nepal-next</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nepal-next/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy New Year&lt;/strong&gt; Everyone!! 2019 is going to be full of adventures, for sure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20181226_085115.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20181226_085115.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is the update&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending Christmas together in my home town, Joe left to Nepal. We are going to join him in 2 days!! &lt;strong&gt;He has a new job&lt;/strong&gt; managing a tuberculosis project in Western Nepal. The plan is to live there for about 6 months but it is all pretty flexible! So, we’ll see!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20181226_131100.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20181226_131100.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are travelling to Kathmandu&lt;/strong&gt; on Sunday. It’s a 6 hour 20 minute flight to Doha plus a 4 hour 20 mintue flight to Kathmandu. My father will be travelling with me and the kids, and he’ll stay for a week with us discovering Nepal for a bit! That will be very helpful because flying with both kids on 2 long night flights by myself could have been very hard… So I am very thankful for that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_IMG_0123.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_IMG_0123.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I am finishing &lt;strong&gt;packing our stuff&lt;/strong&gt;! Basically clothes, medicines, toiletries, school supplies, and a few books and toys. I still need to decide if we are taking our travel crib for Galileo! We are trying to pack light because once we get there, we still don’t have a house, so that means it will be a period (hopefully short) of transition until we settle in to our new live there! Plus, we have learned that whatever we don’t have with us we can buy there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to live in Pyuthan, &lt;strong&gt;a little town on the western part of Nepal&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s in the “hills” region: very rural, and very pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20190103_115150.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20190103_115150.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have asked me “No et fa mandra marxar?” (“Is it hard to leave”?), &lt;strong&gt;“Do you really feel like moving again?”&lt;/strong&gt;. And I know, for a lot of people this kind of life we are living the past few years, moving every 6 to 10 months from one place to another sounds crazy and scary and exhausting! &lt;strong&gt;It is not for everyone&lt;/strong&gt;! And most provably we are not going to always live like this. But right now, that’s what we want to do! Joe got the opportunity to work for this amazing project and we talked a lot about it and finally decided that we do want the adventure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like traveling and discovering new places! Our kids are still young! Ramona is in school and likes it but she is also excited about what she calls &lt;strong&gt;“mama school”&lt;/strong&gt; (I am going to be home-schoooling her these months) and I am pretty excited too, to be honest! She is still so little and as a stay-at-home mom and teacher, it feels hard for me to not be the one spending the most time with her! It’s going to be a challenge but I am happy that we have the opportunity to do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know it is not going to be easy! &lt;strong&gt;Changes are always scary and hard&lt;/strong&gt;! If we want easy and comfortable we would stay where we are, because we have a very good life right now! &lt;strong&gt;But we decided we want adventure&lt;/strong&gt; and that’s what we are doing! We don’t know where we are going to live, we don´t speak the language (that’s the part that I feel the most lazy about…), we don’t know what our day to day is going to look like in a few months, what our dinner will taste like or what our neighbors will be like, but we do know that we wanna be together and we want to do this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_IMG_6517.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_IMG_6517.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will for sure miss our family and friends here, but our home will be as it is when we decide to come back, and there’s always going to be time to be in my hometown again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have so many good memories of our time in Mozambique, for example. It was insanely hot there, and there were mosquitoes that could kill you, but there were also amazing beaches, and great people, and Ramona running barefoot in our yard, and so many precious moments that we wouldn’t change for anything! And this time around, Galileo will turn one in Nepal, and take his first steps there, and we will discover new villages together, and try spicy foods and who know what else!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/20190106_221010-ANIMATION.gif&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/20190106_221010-ANIMATION.gif&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That is the magic of traveling&lt;/strong&gt;! A big world to discover out there and we are ready for it! Will you follow along?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">Happy New Year Everyone!! 2019 is going to be full of adventures, for sure!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Homemade Christmas gifts ideas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/christmas-gifts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homemade Christmas gifts ideas" /><published>2018-12-21T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2018-12-21T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/christmas-gifts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/christmas-gifts/">&lt;p&gt;We have never been a family of giving a lot of gifts for Christmas! Actually, because the last few Christmases we have been living in different countries (2017 in Amsterdam, 2016 in Mozambique, 2015 between the USA and Catalonia, …) I could say that &lt;strong&gt;we had calmer Christmases than average&lt;/strong&gt;. We feel like our kids already have a lot and we (the adults) don’t want much (and we have a lot). And travelling so much makes you realize even more that we don’t really need anything!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6313.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6313.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this year, instead of buying a lot of things, I have been &lt;strong&gt;trying to think of meaningful gifts&lt;/strong&gt;, useful things that my family and friends could enjoy, that I could make with my hands, some of them with Ramona’s help, and here is a list of 7 ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Waldorf window stars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_3071.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_3071.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are beautiful to decorate your windows, especially when the sun come trough! They are easy and fun to make! We even organized an evening with my girlfriends to make some while listening to Christmas music and drinking hot tea! There are a lot of different ones, from very simple to more complicated and beautiful ones! You can make them small and give them as a complement with your gift wrapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181218_223205.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181218_223205.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make them you just need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the specific beeswax paper (you can find it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Mercurius-Assorted-Colors-sheets-Square/dp/B004IORPWU/ref=sr_1_fkmr1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1545338719&amp;amp;sr=8-1-fkmr1&amp;amp;keywords=beeswax+paper+waldorf+stars&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.demicasaalmundo.com/shop/manualidades-waldorf/1202-bloc-surtido-100-hojas-papel-encerado-para-estrellas-waldorf.html?search_query=papel&amp;amp;results=68&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a glue stick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a sharpe knife.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181218_223216.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181218_223216.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Beeswax Candels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theis is a very easy craft to do with the little ones and such a nice present. Beeswax candles are made out of 100% natural beeswax and they smell so good. Pure Beeswax Candles also burn with almost no smoke and clean the air by releasing negative ions into the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181217_192525.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181217_192525.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make them you just need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100% beeswax honeycomb sheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cotton wick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181217_193402.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181217_193402.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Beeswax Christmas tree ornaments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the same beeswax sheets and some cookie cutters we made Chrsitmas tree ornaments with Ramona! So simple but so cute, don’t you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6309.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6309.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6311.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6311.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Lip balm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also made our own lip balm, together with Ramona. I really wanted to make my own lip balm for the longest time and finally this year I decided to buy the necessery stuff, which is not much, and try it! And we are really happy with the result!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it we used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic Coconut Oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic beeswax pellets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic Shea butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Essential oils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small round tins or other containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6314.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6314.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Essential oils sprays&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started following this super mama, Rachel from the blog  &lt;a href=&quot;https://thetent.com.au/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“The red tent”&lt;/a&gt;
and she inspired me so much. 
One of the things I tried from her blog are the “Relaxing Pillow” and the “Daily Stress-Away” Sprays. Learning more about essential oils and discovering this new world is fascinating! So, go check her out, maybe it will inspire you too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6317.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6317.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Granola&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been making our own granola for the past 6 months. Almost every week I make a new batch. We love it so much, so simple and so delicious. It is a way to know what ingredients you are eating and it is a healthier version of the ones you find at the grocery store! We love it for breakfast with yogurt and fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/20180406_121110.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/20180406_121110.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make it mixing the following ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;500gr of oats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 and 1/2 cups of nuts/seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon od salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon of cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cups of melted coconut oil or olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cups of maple syrup or agave syrupe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And bake it in the oven for about 20-25 min. Give it a try, you are going to love it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6305.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6305.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. A painting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ramona loves painting! And people, especially family members, love having her art hanging in their houses! I bought some blank canvases and when Ramona feels like painting she makes her art. We’ve used them as birthday gifts too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6197.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6197.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? What are you going to give to your love ones this Christmas? Do you want to try some of these handmade gift ideas? I would love to know some of your ideas too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6306.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6306.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays y’all!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">We have never been a family of giving a lot of gifts for Christmas! Actually, because the last few Christmases we have been living in different countries (2017 in Amsterdam, 2016 in Mozambique, 2015 between the USA and Catalonia, …) I could say that we had calmer Christmases than average. We feel like our kids already have a lot and we (the adults) don’t want much (and we have a lot). And travelling so much makes you realize even more that we don’t really need anything!!!</summary></entry></feed>