<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-21T13:55:27+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Family on the go</title><subtitle>Reflections on motherhood, parenting, babies and travel</subtitle><author><name>Coloma Farre</name><email>coloma.farre@gmail.com</email><uri>https://github.com/colomafarre</uri></author><entry><title type="html">Homeschooling Ramona in Nepal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/homeschooling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homeschooling Ramona in Nepal" /><published>2019-02-21T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-02-21T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/homeschooling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/homeschooling/">&lt;p&gt;Before we moved to Nepal, Ramona was attending school. The public school of my hometown. She had 11 classmates and a wonderful teacher. She was happy there and we are glad that she was able to do a full a semester of school before we moved to Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we are in Nepal, we thought about sending her to school but the language would be too much of an obstacle (for the moment)… So we decided that &lt;strong&gt;homeschooling her for the time we live here was the best solution&lt;/strong&gt;! She is still very young (3 and a half years old) and I am actually an Early Childhood teacher with 6 years of experience, so teaching doesn’t come new to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_091152.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_091152.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really excited before we moved about this oportunity! Getting materials ready, supplies, ideas, etc. She was too! This past summer I taught an afternoon class in my hometown, where she attended too, and she called it &lt;strong&gt;“Mama school”&lt;/strong&gt;, so that is what we call it now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_144347.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_144347.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we have settled in our new place, we have started “Mama school”, even though she was asking from day one to start school!! We needed a routine, to unpack our bags and settle a little bit and now we are on it! Monday to Friday: Mama School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is our daily rhythm&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wake up (around 7:30), cook and eat breakfast together, Joe goes to work (or starts working from home), I get the kids clean and dressed for the day. We have been playing “hairdresser” as an excuse to do Ramona’s hair in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, around 9, we start with &lt;strong&gt;Circle Time&lt;/strong&gt;. Me and Ramona stand one in front of one another, while Galileo plays around, and we sing some songs and finger play songs together. We always start with the same song, and then I have a list of the ones we know already and the ones I want to teach her, mixing English and Catalan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opening song&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Good morning dear Earth, good morning dear Sun,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good morning dear rocks, and flowers every one,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good morning dear beasts, and birds in the trees,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good morning to you, and good morning to me.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_095528.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_095528.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, we go potty, put our shoes on, drink some water and get ready for our &lt;strong&gt;Morning Walk&lt;/strong&gt;. This has been so far the most enjoyable thing for me (and the kids like it too). Galileo goes in the carrier, on my back, and Ramona walks. Every day &lt;strong&gt;we pick a goal for our walk&lt;/strong&gt;. Sometimes it is to find some flowers for Suman, some rocks to do a craft later, we bring the magnifying glass and look for small things, or we just decide a destination (the big river, the house with the swing, …) and enjoy everything we find on the way. We spend between 45 min and 1 hour wondering around. It has been really nice to walk out of the house first thing in the morning, to be out in nature, seeing the animals, discovering our neighborhood!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_151403.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_151403.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190215_100842.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190215_100842.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_101238.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_101238.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190218_093624.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190218_093624.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we hit back home, Suman is normally there already, getting lunch or laundry ready. We have a &lt;strong&gt;snack&lt;/strong&gt;. Then Galileo may take a nap (he is in the period between needing 1 or 2 naps, depending on how early he woke up that morning) or hang out with her, while me and Ramona work on &lt;strong&gt;the activity of the day&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mondays: &lt;strong&gt;Watercolor painting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tuesdays: &lt;strong&gt;Beeswax modelling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wednsdays: &lt;strong&gt;Coloring with block crayons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thursdays: &lt;strong&gt;Crafting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fridays: &lt;strong&gt;Free day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set the activity out in the porch (we don’t have a table, but the porch steps are working fine for now …), we sing the activity song and we do it together. For exemple, while she paints I paint, which is so nice to have the excuse to paint watercolors again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190212_115939.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190212_115939.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_113306.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190219_113306.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_103905.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_103905.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These may take more or less time, depending on how into it Ramona is in the moment. Sometimes we have time to do another activity after that (from the ones in the following “extra activities” list) or just some &lt;strong&gt;free play time&lt;/strong&gt; before lunch is ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extra activities&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dance class&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Study Nepali&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yoga class&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Holiday crafts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treasure hunt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finger knitting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flower pressing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleaning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_101950.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_101950.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_110446.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_110446.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190218_103648.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190218_103648.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We eat &lt;strong&gt;lunch&lt;/strong&gt; around 12, out in the porch, looking at the people walk by and talking about when I was a kid (Ramona is very into stories about when we were little kids latlely, and loves asking so many questions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_115105.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190220_115105.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it is &lt;strong&gt;story time&lt;/strong&gt; (either me or Joe with Ramona in her room) and &lt;strong&gt;nap time&lt;/strong&gt;. She will not always nap, most days yes, other days she will do quiet time, playing with her dolls and reading books until I tell her is time to get out of the room (after about 1 hour).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Galileo didn’t take a morning nap he will go down after lunch too, if not a little bit later for his second nap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_165304.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/homeschool/20190214_165304.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After nap we have a &lt;strong&gt;snack&lt;/strong&gt; and go out in our front yard for &lt;strong&gt;outdoor free play&lt;/strong&gt;. We hang the hammock, they play in the sand, build sand-casltes with sticks, etc. Normally the neighbor kids join in on the fun too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Joe is done with work, around 6 pm, I start getting dinner ready, we eat together, then bathe (every other day now…), pj’s, teeth, nurse to sleep for Galileo and stories for Ramona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After writting all this I realized that &lt;strong&gt;we spend most of the day outside&lt;/strong&gt; and I love it! The temperature is great right now to be outside most of the time without being too hot or too cold, which is so nice. This rhythm may change and will get reajusted with time for sure, but for now that is what works for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have organized our homeschooling days thinking about Ramona’s needs and &lt;strong&gt;following the Waldorf philosophy&lt;/strong&gt;, inspired by the time I worked at Morning Meadow Waldorf Preeschool and Kindergarten, and with the help of the awesome seasonal guides by  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wholefamilyrhythms.com/product/full-year-guide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Whole Family Rhythms&lt;/a&gt;. Even though we don’t have everything we would like here (no oven to bake bread, no good watercolor paper, etc) we do what we can with what we have! And I feel like it is working! Ramona is learning so much just being outside, observing nature, asking so many questions and creating and imagining her own little world! It is fantastic and I am so happy to be able to walk with her through this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does this sound to you? Would you like to homeschool your kids? What other activities should we add to our list?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">Before we moved to Nepal, Ramona was attending school. The public school of my hometown. She had 11 classmates and a wonderful teacher. She was happy there and we are glad that she was able to do a full a semester of school before we moved to Nepal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life update from Pyuthan, Nepal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nepal-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life update from Pyuthan, Nepal" /><published>2019-02-18T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-02-18T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nepal-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nepal-update/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_123107.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_123107.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello from rural Nepal! We’ve spent &lt;strong&gt;a little over a month in this country already&lt;/strong&gt;! I can’t belive it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8929.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8929.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8898.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8898.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It has been a kind of crazy month for us&lt;/strong&gt;! When we arrived we spent a few days in Kathmandu, a few days in Pokhara, then a week in Pyuthan (here) but staying at the hotel while looking for a house, and then back to Kathmandu for almost 2 weeks! Last week we finally settled in our new home (what we call “&lt;strong&gt;home sweet home&lt;/strong&gt;”) in the town of Bijuwar, in Pyuthan district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_20190211_125349.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_20190211_125349.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really like our new place, especially the location. It is a little bit far from the “downtown” area (15 min walk) but it is so peaceful and quiet! &lt;strong&gt;Our street is a dirt road where no cars go by&lt;/strong&gt;, a few motorcicles and sometimes you’ll see a tractor, but mostly just people walking. The neighbors have goats, cows, and chickens, there’s a field full of yellow flowers in front of our house, a little creek in the back and 3 minutes down the road we get to the main river, Ramona’s new favorite spot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_103246.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_103246.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_103343.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190216_103343.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She really likes to play close to the water creeks, pretending she is fishing, following the little paths next to the water, jumping and climbing around. Galileo loves crawling in our front yard, playing with sticks and getting dirty from head to toe! It is really nice to &lt;strong&gt;be able to be in nature just stepping out of the house&lt;/strong&gt;! And our favorite hang out spot: our porch. We spend so much time on it, we even have lunch out there too. And the hammock on it is the favorite of all the neighborhood kids!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190211_150717.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190211_150717.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About our house&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s a 3 bedroom house, with a very basic kitchen (sink and portable gas stove, table and 4 plastic chairs), and bathroom with a faucet (without hot water) for taking bucket baths, toilet (which we installed. Before there was only a squat toilet), and sink. There’s a rooftop where we hang our clothes to dry. It is very simple but very nice by local standards!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical houses here are made out of mud and wood, with little windows and low ceilings. People wash clothes and dishes outside. They even wash their teeth and hair outside! Homes are basically to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190218_100743.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190218_100743.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t have a heating system (nobody does). So what that means is that at night is pretty cold (we have thick blankets and pj’s) and in the morning too, but during the day, luckily, it gets warmer already, so we try to open the windows when it is nice outside so the warm air comes in the house, and basicly &lt;strong&gt;just dress acording to the temperature&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not having hot water is also quite the experience&lt;/strong&gt;. We warm up water with a big kettle for bucket baths for the kids, and we (the adults) take showers during the day when the air is not so cold! I wash my hair seperatly, with my clothes on, which I’ve learned it is better for me, less painful! Joe times his baths to be right after exercise, when his body temperature is hightest. Washing dishes with cold water when it is cold it is pretty unpleasant too…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best thing is&lt;/strong&gt;, we have Suman, a woman that comes every morning, from Monday to Friday, to help us with the kids, with translation, with going to the market, around the house, everything. She is wonderful!! She cooks us delicious lunch, she likes to play with the kids, washes clothes (by hand!!), and is basically our hero here! She knows where to find stuff, she is a mom herself, she anticipates our needs and in general, she and her husband have been very helpful for our family to quickly feel like home in our new house!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190215_124406.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190215_124406.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not having a supermarket to go grocery shopping&lt;/strong&gt;, just little stores with what it feels to us like random stuff, it makes it hard to find what we need. A lot of people have asked about differences on the food here so here is the sum up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fruits and vegetables are everywhere but not a huge variety.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fruits in Pyuthan: oranges (delicios but full of seeds), bananas, red apples, grapes and coconuts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In other areas you can find more variety. Like Kathmandu had avocaDos, kiwis, pineapple, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vegetables in Pyuthan: cabbage, coliflower, broccoli, green beans, green peppers, potatoes, tomatoes, red onions, garlic and sometimes I find zuchinni and eggplants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8918.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_8918.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fruits and vegetables taste and look the same.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They eat eggs, chicken and buffalo but a lot of people are vegetarian.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They cook a lot of beans (a lot of different kinds of lentils, black beans, chickpeas, …)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They use a lot of spices and food coloring in their food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They eat dal bhat (rice and lentil soup) &lt;strong&gt;everyday&lt;/strong&gt;, for breakfast and dinner. For lunch they eat some kind of fried stuff like samosas, momos (dumplings), etc. filled with vegetables, chicken, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190206_121700.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190206_121700.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rice is the main food, I would say! And they generaly eat it with their hands!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We can’t find much refrigerated stuff here… We don’t have a fridge either! So, really missing cheese!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can get milk, but it’s not pasteurized (so you have to boil it).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We couldn’t find a coffee maker so instant coffee will do for now (with powdered milk!). They drink more tea than coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190213_121519.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190213_121519.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we have been eating rice everyday too! Thankfully, both Ramona and Galileo like dal bhat already, which makes it easier around here! And I have to say, for being a go-to food, it is pretty nutritious and healty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190217_174818.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190217_174818.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somebody asked about &lt;strong&gt;the most challenging thing so far&lt;/strong&gt;. I would say the first days here in Pyuthan were the hardest. We were staying at a hotel, all packed in a room, with no hot water either, sharing one towel, discovering still the sorroundings, etc. The kids where not used to the spiciness of the food yet, the cold nights in the hotel room, and having to get dressed in the cold morning room too, Ramona missed Santa Coloma a lot, etc… &lt;strong&gt;Transitional periods&lt;/strong&gt;, when you still don’t have a proper place to put your stuff and a kitchen to prepare your own snacks, &lt;strong&gt;are the hardest I think&lt;/strong&gt;. Now we kind of have a routine, our stuff is more or less in place (we still have to buy some furniture) and we feel settled which helps with everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_1160.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/IMG_1160.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The easiest thing so far, which I dind’t anticipated&lt;/strong&gt;, was actually the food. I thought I (personaly) wouldn’t like it as much as I like it already! It is spicy sometimes, but just the amount of spiciness I can tolerate, kind of! And in general it is very tasty and yummy (altough very repeptitive, I have to say!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190211_084949.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nepalupdate/20190211_084949.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will share more about our day to day soon (I feel like there is so much to say,but I don’t want the post to be too long!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;strong&gt;a video of our Saturday morning&lt;/strong&gt; last weekend, when we when down to the river and to eat lunch to our favorite restaurant in town!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a9F1S4SlnZU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading us!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Galileo turned 1*</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/galileo-turns-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Galileo turned 1*" /><published>2019-01-26T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-01-26T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/galileo-turns-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/galileo-turns-1/">&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;January 21st, 2019 Galileo turned 1&lt;/strong&gt;. One year being a family of 4, of Ramona being a big sister! It may have not been the day I imagined for his first birthday, but it sure was special!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/20190121_161026.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/20190121_161026.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day before we travelled from Pokhara to Pyuthan, which was a &lt;strong&gt;9 hour car ride&lt;/strong&gt; through crazy windy roads with both kids and all our stuff, and an amazing driver that drove us safely to Jumri (Pyuthan district), Nepal! The day went as good as it could go but it still was exhausting! The next day I woke up with a bad cold and I had to be in bed most of the day. But Joe, Ramona and Galileo went on some walks to explore our new home town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8258.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8258.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People when they see us here they are mesmerized! They stop what they are doing and stair at us! We are the first white poeple in town for a long time, apparently! &lt;strong&gt;Everybody wants to hold Galileo&lt;/strong&gt; and take selfies with him, and he seems to not mind it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8328.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8328.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, before sunset, we decided to &lt;strong&gt;throw a little party&lt;/strong&gt; for Galileo! We grabbed a plate, we put some cookies and cut out oranges, we stuck a candle (that I got in Pokhara beforehand) in one of the oranges, asked for some matches at the hotel, grabbed the 3 ballons I had in my bag (I always carry ballons with me while travelling, great entertainment in aerports, etc.) and went out to find a good spot for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_20190121_165930.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_20190121_165930.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had &lt;strong&gt;the crown&lt;/strong&gt; I made for Ramona’s birthdays (see Ramona’s first Birthday party &lt;a href=&quot;http://familyonthego.life/ramona-turns-1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) with the number one for Galileo! He didn’t want to wear it much but there are still some pictures with him wearing it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8268.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8268.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sang the song for him and Ramona helped him blow the candle, which surprisingly kept re-lighting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8297.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8297.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He enjoyed his cookies and oranges!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8286.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8286.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the time to do that there were a lot of people around us, especially women and kids, that had stopped and enjoyed the celebration with us! We shared chocolate and cookies with them, the kids played with the ballons, they passed Galileo around and we had a nice time together. Even if we couldn’t talk much, everybody was happy and it was really sweet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8278.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8278.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8270.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8270.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8321.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8321.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8302.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/galileoturned1/0000_IMG_8302.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is &lt;strong&gt;the video&lt;/strong&gt; of the first year of Galileo in this world, with him looking so tiny at the beggining, a lot of love form her sister, a lot of laughing and travelling around the world! Lucky you Galileo, you have a family that loves you SO much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ltl6yHxpQ88&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">On January 21st, 2019 Galileo turned 1. One year being a family of 4, of Ramona being a big sister! It may have not been the day I imagined for his first birthday, but it sure was special!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First week in Nepal - Kathmandu and Pokhara</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/first-week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First week in Nepal - Kathmandu and Pokhara" /><published>2019-01-25T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-01-25T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/first-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/first-week/">&lt;p&gt;On January 13th 2019 my dad, Ramona, Galileo and I flew from Barcelona to Doha and then to Kathmandu, where Joe was waiting for us at the airport. After a night of little sleep (at least for the adults) we got to Nepal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:01:20.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:01:20.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:25:28.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:25:28.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flying with &lt;strong&gt;Qatar Airways&lt;/strong&gt; was great! Very helpful flight attendants, spacious seats, with the option of having the baby bassinet for Galileo (that he used for a while, even if he almost didn’t fit!), and the flight was not full so we had a couple extra seats for us! So we flew as comfortable as it gets for being in economy class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:35:33.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:13-23:35:33.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got to Kathmandu, after dealing with all the visa and paper stuff we took a taxi to the hotel. We stayed at the &lt;strong&gt;Taleju Boutique Hotel in the Thamel neighborhood&lt;/strong&gt; for 3 nights. It was nice to have a patio where the kids could run/crawl around, especially after seeing how busy the city can be!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-09:54:54.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-09:54:54.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent those tree days &lt;strong&gt;exploring the city, at a family friendly pace&lt;/strong&gt;! We walked a lot, bought some souvenirs for my dad to take back to the family, we visited some Buddhist and Hindu temples and in general, we tried to get a feel for the country and its culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:33:24.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:33:24.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The city of Kathmadu is really busy and felt chaotic&lt;/strong&gt;! There’s a lot of traffic, very narrow streets and no sidewalks for pedestrians (in most areas), so it felt a little overwhelming with the little ones. In general, it was a lot to take in for the first days in a new country! You know how it is, when you don’t have enough eyes to look at everything that’s happening around you!? Ramona was a little bit confused the first days. She would observe everything and ask you things like “Why do they have that red spot on their forehead?” or “Why do they where sandals if it’s cold?” She notices everything and I feel like the first days where hard for her (I guess for all of us!!), but it is also amazing how quickly we can adapt!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:43:49.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:43:49.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:44:10.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:44:10.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:49:06.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-07:49:06.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-08:21:44.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-08:21:44.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-09:20:04.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-09:20:04.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the most intense experiences we had&lt;/strong&gt; was when we visited the Shree Pashupatinath Temple, during a Hindu festival. We paid a guide so he could tell is a litlle bit about what was happening, because that’s one thing we quickly realized, how little we know about their traditions and how different the cultures can be!. We saw a lot of monkeys running around and eating bananas and oranges. Apparently they are protected, just like cows, and feeding them gives the person good karma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:06:02.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:06:02.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;strong&gt;the most breathtaking thing&lt;/strong&gt; was seeing the cremation of a dead body, right next to the river, and the ceremony that that involved, while an festival was happening at the same time, on the other side of the river, with music and dancing and all!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:11:20.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:11:20.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:35:11.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:15-15:35:11.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have never guessed that I would see a body burning right in front of me, and I have to say, it was quite unsettling, but after some time and seeing how they experience it, I think it was a very cultural and human way to get to know them better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-10:46:35.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-10:46:35.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Yummy roasted corn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-10:47:48.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-10:47:48.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; So much love!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-11:07:59.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-11:07:59.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Trying to take a family picture!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-15:47:40.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:16-15:47:40.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; He made us these catalan patches for our bags!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-09:02:02.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-09:02:02.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-09:05:04.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-09:05:04.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forth day &lt;strong&gt;we took a flight to Pokhara&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:02:19.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:02:19.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the smallest plane I’ve ever been on! There were 18 passangers total! It was quite the experience, but actually more pleasant than what I anticipated! It was such a short flight (about 20 min) with beautiful views of the Himalayas. So, no complaints!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:02:46.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:02:46.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:06:00.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-10:06:00.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pokhara is a beautiful city next to this big lake, sorounded by mountains! It is very touristy, because it’s known as a gateway to the Annapurna Circuit. But there’s much less polution than Kathmandu, and it is a little bit more organized because it’s a newer city. We stayed at the &lt;strong&gt;Vardan Resort N’ Apartment&lt;/strong&gt;. It was very nice with the kids too because we had a little porch and some grassy area for them to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the highlights of Pokhara:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-12:09:11.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-12:09:11.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sailing around the lake!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-12:15:46.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-12:15:46.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pokhara “Disneyland” Funpark! A little bit scketchy but pretty entertaining!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-13:08:24.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-13:08:24.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roasted corn. I Already loved corn but seeing Ramona starting to love it is even better than eating it myself!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-13:33:13.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-13:33:13.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The beautiful views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-16:45:02.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:17-16:45:02.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And for sure, the craziest thing was &lt;strong&gt;Paragliding with my dad&lt;/strong&gt;!!! (see more in the video below!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-12:58:59.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-12:58:59.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We did some hiking, with our new friends (and baby) we made at the hotel!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-13:53:25.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-13:53:25.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-14:06:05.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-14:06:05.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-14:27:55.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-14:27:55.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-15:07:21.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:18-15:07:21.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was a great discovery! Getting out of the big city, getting to see some more of the country, it was a good decision to go to Pokhara for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:19-11:17:59.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/firstweeknepal/2019:01:19-11:17:59.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that my dad when back to Catalonia and we continued our journey to western Nepal. But I’ll tell you more about that in another post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is &lt;strong&gt;a video of my dad’s visit&lt;/strong&gt;, during this first days of the whole family together discovering Nepal! I hope you like it! And maybe get excited to come visit too!?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tMOL1stzQfQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NAMASTE !!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">On January 13th 2019 my dad, Ramona, Galileo and I flew from Barcelona to Doha and then to Kathmandu, where Joe was waiting for us at the airport. After a night of little sleep (at least for the adults) we got to Nepal!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Next destination -&amp;gt; Nepal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nepal-next/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Next destination -&gt; Nepal" /><published>2019-01-11T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-01-11T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nepal-next</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nepal-next/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy New Year&lt;/strong&gt; Everyone!! 2019 is going to be full of adventures, for sure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20181226_085115.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20181226_085115.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is the update&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending Christmas together in my home town, Joe left to Nepal. We are going to join him in 2 days!! &lt;strong&gt;He has a new job&lt;/strong&gt; managing a tuberculosis project in Western Nepal. The plan is to live there for about 6 months but it is all pretty flexible! So, we’ll see!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20181226_131100.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20181226_131100.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are travelling to Kathmandu&lt;/strong&gt; on Sunday. It’s a 6 hour 20 minute flight to Doha plus a 4 hour 20 mintue flight to Kathmandu. My father will be travelling with me and the kids, and he’ll stay for a week with us discovering Nepal for a bit! That will be very helpful because flying with both kids on 2 long night flights by myself could have been very hard… So I am very thankful for that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_IMG_0123.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_IMG_0123.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I am finishing &lt;strong&gt;packing our stuff&lt;/strong&gt;! Basically clothes, medicines, toiletries, school supplies, and a few books and toys. I still need to decide if we are taking our travel crib for Galileo! We are trying to pack light because once we get there, we still don’t have a house, so that means it will be a period (hopefully short) of transition until we settle in to our new live there! Plus, we have learned that whatever we don’t have with us we can buy there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to live in Pyuthan, &lt;strong&gt;a little town on the western part of Nepal&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s in the “hills” region: very rural, and very pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20190103_115150.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_20190103_115150.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have asked me “No et fa mandra marxar?” (“Is it hard to leave”?), &lt;strong&gt;“Do you really feel like moving again?”&lt;/strong&gt;. And I know, for a lot of people this kind of life we are living the past few years, moving every 6 to 10 months from one place to another sounds crazy and scary and exhausting! &lt;strong&gt;It is not for everyone&lt;/strong&gt;! And most provably we are not going to always live like this. But right now, that’s what we want to do! Joe got the opportunity to work for this amazing project and we talked a lot about it and finally decided that we do want the adventure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like traveling and discovering new places! Our kids are still young! Ramona is in school and likes it but she is also excited about what she calls &lt;strong&gt;“mama school”&lt;/strong&gt; (I am going to be home-schoooling her these months) and I am pretty excited too, to be honest! She is still so little and as a stay-at-home mom and teacher, it feels hard for me to not be the one spending the most time with her! It’s going to be a challenge but I am happy that we have the opportunity to do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know it is not going to be easy! &lt;strong&gt;Changes are always scary and hard&lt;/strong&gt;! If we want easy and comfortable we would stay where we are, because we have a very good life right now! &lt;strong&gt;But we decided we want adventure&lt;/strong&gt; and that’s what we are doing! We don’t know where we are going to live, we don´t speak the language (that’s the part that I feel the most lazy about…), we don’t know what our day to day is going to look like in a few months, what our dinner will taste like or what our neighbors will be like, but we do know that we wanna be together and we want to do this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_IMG_6517.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/0000_IMG_6517.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will for sure miss our family and friends here, but our home will be as it is when we decide to come back, and there’s always going to be time to be in my hometown again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have so many good memories of our time in Mozambique, for example. It was insanely hot there, and there were mosquitoes that could kill you, but there were also amazing beaches, and great people, and Ramona running barefoot in our yard, and so many precious moments that we wouldn’t change for anything! And this time around, Galileo will turn one in Nepal, and take his first steps there, and we will discover new villages together, and try spicy foods and who know what else!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/nextnepal/20190106_221010-ANIMATION.gif&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/nextnepal/20190106_221010-ANIMATION.gif&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That is the magic of traveling&lt;/strong&gt;! A big world to discover out there and we are ready for it! Will you follow along?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">Happy New Year Everyone!! 2019 is going to be full of adventures, for sure!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Homemade Christmas gifts ideas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/christmas-gifts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homemade Christmas gifts ideas" /><published>2018-12-21T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2018-12-21T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/christmas-gifts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/christmas-gifts/">&lt;p&gt;We have never been a family of giving a lot of gifts for Christmas! Actually, because the last few Christmases we have been living in different countries (2017 in Amsterdam, 2016 in Mozambique, 2015 between the USA and Catalonia, …) I could say that &lt;strong&gt;we had calmer Christmases than average&lt;/strong&gt;. We feel like our kids already have a lot and we (the adults) don’t want much (and we have a lot). And travelling so much makes you realize even more that we don’t really need anything!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6313.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6313.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this year, instead of buying a lot of things, I have been &lt;strong&gt;trying to think of meaningful gifts&lt;/strong&gt;, useful things that my family and friends could enjoy, that I could make with my hands, some of them with Ramona’s help, and here is a list of 7 ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Waldorf window stars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_3071.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_3071.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are beautiful to decorate your windows, especially when the sun come trough! They are easy and fun to make! We even organized an evening with my girlfriends to make some while listening to Christmas music and drinking hot tea! There are a lot of different ones, from very simple to more complicated and beautiful ones! You can make them small and give them as a complement with your gift wrapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181218_223205.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181218_223205.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make them you just need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the specific beeswax paper (you can find it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Mercurius-Assorted-Colors-sheets-Square/dp/B004IORPWU/ref=sr_1_fkmr1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1545338719&amp;amp;sr=8-1-fkmr1&amp;amp;keywords=beeswax+paper+waldorf+stars&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;
or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.demicasaalmundo.com/shop/manualidades-waldorf/1202-bloc-surtido-100-hojas-papel-encerado-para-estrellas-waldorf.html?search_query=papel&amp;amp;results=68&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a glue stick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a sharpe knife.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181218_223216.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181218_223216.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Beeswax Candels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theis is a very easy craft to do with the little ones and such a nice present. Beeswax candles are made out of 100% natural beeswax and they smell so good. Pure Beeswax Candles also burn with almost no smoke and clean the air by releasing negative ions into the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181217_192525.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181217_192525.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make them you just need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100% beeswax honeycomb sheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cotton wick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181217_193402.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_20181217_193402.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Beeswax Christmas tree ornaments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the same beeswax sheets and some cookie cutters we made Chrsitmas tree ornaments with Ramona! So simple but so cute, don’t you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6309.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6309.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6311.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6311.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Lip balm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also made our own lip balm, together with Ramona. I really wanted to make my own lip balm for the longest time and finally this year I decided to buy the necessery stuff, which is not much, and try it! And we are really happy with the result!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it we used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic Coconut Oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic beeswax pellets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organic Shea butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Essential oils&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small round tins or other containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6314.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6314.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Essential oils sprays&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started following this super mama, Rachel from the blog  &lt;a href=&quot;https://thetent.com.au/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“The red tent”&lt;/a&gt;
and she inspired me so much. 
One of the things I tried from her blog are the “Relaxing Pillow” and the “Daily Stress-Away” Sprays. Learning more about essential oils and discovering this new world is fascinating! So, go check her out, maybe it will inspire you too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6317.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6317.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Granola&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been making our own granola for the past 6 months. Almost every week I make a new batch. We love it so much, so simple and so delicious. It is a way to know what ingredients you are eating and it is a healthier version of the ones you find at the grocery store! We love it for breakfast with yogurt and fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/20180406_121110.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/20180406_121110.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make it mixing the following ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;500gr of oats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 and 1/2 cups of nuts/seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon od salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon of cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cups of melted coconut oil or olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 cups of maple syrup or agave syrupe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And bake it in the oven for about 20-25 min. Give it a try, you are going to love it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6305.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6305.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. A painting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ramona loves painting! And people, especially family members, love having her art hanging in their houses! I bought some blank canvases and when Ramona feels like painting she makes her art. We’ve used them as birthday gifts too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6197.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6197.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? What are you going to give to your love ones this Christmas? Do you want to try some of these handmade gift ideas? I would love to know some of your ideas too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6306.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/christmasgifts/0000_IMG_6306.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays y’all!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">We have never been a family of giving a lot of gifts for Christmas! Actually, because the last few Christmases we have been living in different countries (2017 in Amsterdam, 2016 in Mozambique, 2015 between the USA and Catalonia, …) I could say that we had calmer Christmases than average. We feel like our kids already have a lot and we (the adults) don’t want much (and we have a lot). And travelling so much makes you realize even more that we don’t really need anything!!!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lots of Advent Calendar ideas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Advent-calendar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lots of Advent Calendar ideas" /><published>2018-11-16T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2018-11-16T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Advent-calendar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Advent-calendar/">&lt;p&gt;Like the song says: &lt;strong&gt;“It’s begining to look a lot like Cristmas…!!”&lt;/strong&gt; Well, here not really yet, but we are getting closer to December. And because time flies lately, I have started thinking about advent calendar ideas. &lt;strong&gt;Maybe you too!?&lt;/strong&gt; I want to share some of the ideas I have in my head that may be useful to create your own personal advent calendar at home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7102.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7102.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(The pictures from this post are from last year, which explains my big baby bump and Ramona looking so small!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year was the first time &lt;strong&gt;we introduced this tradition in our family&lt;/strong&gt;! Ramona was 2 and a half and she was begining to understand the anticipation and liked the tradition of opening a little something every morning! So this year we are repeting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7113.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7113.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To create my advent calendar I used&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A wodden branch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;String and scisors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Envelops, wrapping paper and tape&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A black pen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And a bunch of ideas (that I am going to share with you here!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7118.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7118.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need much to make &lt;strong&gt;a beautiful and fun activitiy for the whole family&lt;/strong&gt; that will guide you from December 1st all the way to Christmas day! There are very different kinds of advent calendars (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.es/cfarrlpez/advent-calendar/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; is full of good ideas, and that’s where I found my inspiration last year). This year I wanna try to creat a cloth one that we can use every year, but we’ll see if I have time to make it!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, 3 steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide what you want to use to make your advent calendar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decide what kind of surprises will be in it, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a good time every day to open them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t have to be gifts or material stuff. It can also be activities to do together as a family, for example. Some people wrap 24 wintery/chrismy books and they open one each day to read! Last year we did &lt;strong&gt;a mix of small presents, books and family adventures&lt;/strong&gt; and we opened them every morning after breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are my ideas, more than 24, so you can chose the ones that suit your family best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FAMILY ACTIVITIES&lt;/strong&gt;
(Some we did last year, some we are going to do this year and some you may be able to do if you live in a big city)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s take family Chrismy photos for our Christmas cards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s have dinner with candles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s go find the “Tió” (catalan tradition)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let’s bake Christmas cookies and decorate them
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/Screenshot_20171222-145502.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/Screenshot_20171222-145502.png&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s go to the Christmas market&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s go for a walk after dinner to see the Christmas lights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s decorate the Christmas tree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let’s go ice-skating
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_8344.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_8344.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s eat in a restaurant today&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s write our Christmas cards and send them to friends and family&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s make pizzas and watch a classic Chrismy movie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s play Christmas music and have a family dance party&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let’s have hot chocolate together
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7891.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7891.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s bring some Christmas cookies to our neighbors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s go caroling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s choose some toys and books and bring them to a house in need&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let’s go get a Christmas tree
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/0000_20171223_172049.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/0000_20171223_172049.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s dress up funny and take family selfies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s make window stars&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s have breakfast for dinner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s talk about things that make us happy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s dry some oranges and make a garland&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s make cinnamon scented playdough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LITTLE GIFTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modeling Beeswax&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stickers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New tooth brush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kids Tattoos
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/20180127_181651.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/20180127_181651.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marbles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little felted animal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sidewalk chalk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hair acessories (bow, headband, …)
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/0000_20171220_090603.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/0000_20171220_090603.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Books: there are so many good books about winter and Christmas, and there’s no such thing as too many books. Ramona’s favorites for this season are: “The Tomten”  by Astrid Lindgren, “The snowman” by Raymond Briggs, and “Little lost angel” by Janet Field Heath. But &lt;a href=&quot;http://twentyventi.blogspot.com/search?q=winter+books#.W-3cimNKg8o&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://babyccinokids.com/blog/2015/11/19/christmas-book-advent-calendar-updated/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; are 2 super lists of amazing books if you need more inspiration!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_8165.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_8165.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Underwear or socks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Little Christmas tree decoration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finger puppet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small puzzle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bubble wand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kinder egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beeswax crazons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… Anything small your kids will like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? Are you going to do an advent calendar at home? Is this somehting your family did growing up? Actually, here in Catalonia it was not really a tradition before (it’s a German tradition) but I think is a good one to adopt!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7111.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/advent/0000_IMG_7111.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">Like the song says: “It’s begining to look a lot like Cristmas…!!” Well, here not really yet, but we are getting closer to December. And because time flies lately, I have started thinking about advent calendar ideas. Maybe you too!? I want to share some of the ideas I have in my head that may be useful to create your own personal advent calendar at home!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How we do Waldorf at home</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Waldorf-at-home/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How we do Waldorf at home" /><published>2018-10-25T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2018-10-25T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Waldorf-at-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Waldorf-at-home/">&lt;p&gt;As you may know, I really like &lt;strong&gt;Waldorf Education&lt;/strong&gt;. I am not a certified Waldorf teacher but I did work as an Assistant teacher at Morning Meadow and Spanish teacher at Heart Pine Waldorf school for 2 years while I lived in Gainesville, Florida. I learned a lot from amazing teachers there and it was a very revealing and uplifting period of my life! Learning about a different way of teaching, of approaching education trough a different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_20140904_082931nopm.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_20140904_082931nopm.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Pictures from Morning Meadow, the Early Childhood Waldorf School where I used to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_20140926_145103.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_20140926_145103.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The natural materials, the sense of beauty, the love for art and manual things, the respect towards children, the rhythm, the connection with nature and the seasons&lt;/strong&gt;, … It all felt right to me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSC00049.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSC00049.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Pictures from Heart Pine, the Primary Waldorf school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSC00496.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSC00496.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSC00237.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSC00237.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fell in love with the Waldorf education and since then, I’ve tried to keep it present at home with my little ones. I am not going to talk about what Waldorf Education is because it would be the longest post, but you can read more about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sunbridge.edu/about/waldorf-education/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; here&lt;/a&gt; or watch about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WcC4znsu2Ac&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do want to tell you is &lt;strong&gt;what we do to bring the Waldorf essence to our daily family rhythm at home&lt;/strong&gt;. Here are 7 easy applicable ideas to do so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. EMBRACE NATURE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go outside every day. Not only out in the streets but try to go to places where you can connect with nature, without cars around, where the kids can play with fallen leaves and rocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/pedres.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/pedres.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_1560.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_1560.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_0840.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_0840.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you can bring a little bit of outside nature in your house! You can create a seasonal &lt;strong&gt;nature table&lt;/strong&gt;, with representative elements from the season. Go on a &lt;strong&gt;nature walk&lt;/strong&gt;, bring a basket with you, gather nature’s little treasures like pinecones, flowers or nuts and create a little corner to display them in your living room. The kids can help arrange it. Include some color apropiate silks, maybe add some felted creatures and there you have it, your own nature table!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1458.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1458.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1454.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1454.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. THINK ABOUT YOUR FAMILY RHYTHM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily, weekly and seasonal rhythms &lt;strong&gt;help the kids feel secure and happy&lt;/strong&gt;, because they know what to expect and they like the anticipation. Think about your family, your needs and strucure your day in a way that works for YOUR family. &lt;strong&gt;Sleeptimes and mealtimes&lt;/strong&gt; are very important to provide the basics but most important habits on kids. Not only an early bedtime is necessary for kids to sleep enough hours each night, but also daytime napping (or quite time, if they are done napping during the day). Make mealtimes a good quality family time. Sit together at the table, without distractions, talk about the day and enjoy good, nourishing food together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSC00047.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSC00047.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. EMBRACE TRADITIONS AND SEASONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think also about which &lt;strong&gt;traditions&lt;/strong&gt; you want to establish as a family like pancakes for breakfast on Saturdays or pizza night on Fridays! And which &lt;strong&gt;festivals&lt;/strong&gt; you want to celebrate every season, like the “Castanyada” baking &lt;a href=&quot;http://familyonthego.life/fall/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Panellets&lt;/a&gt;  or decorating the Christmas tree together, and repeat them every year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSCF0508.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_DSCF0508.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. NATURAL AND OPEN-ENDED TOYS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toys are important for kids’ free play time but that doesn’t mean they need a lot of them. The best toys are the ones that are very simple and can become several different things (open-ended toys), made out of natural materials. Once I read somewhere: imgine closing your eyes and feeling different toys with your hands. Can you imagine how different it would be to feel a plastic toy than for exemple a wooden toy, or a doll made out of natural wool instead of plastic!? &lt;strong&gt;We need to be thoughful about which toys we bring in our house&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1443.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1443.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1438.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1438.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1460.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1460.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1437.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1437.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the way we store them and organize them will help the way kids play with them. Put the toy where kids can reach them, and organize each kind of toy in a different basket so your children know where to find each thing. Clean up may need some help but having your toys organized will ensure a less kaotic play time too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1441.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1441.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1439.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1439.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My top 5 favorite toys:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play silks&lt;/strong&gt;. Ramona will play for hours with her colorful silks! They can become a skirt, cape, hat, baby carrier, a blanket for her doll, … Anything the imagination wants! A must have! You can find them &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.demicasaalmundo.com/shop/juego/455-panuelo-de-juego-arcoiris-de-seda-natural.html?search_query=seda&amp;amp;results=27&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Play kitchen corner&lt;/strong&gt; with some kitchen utensils and food. Kids love to imitate us, our daily activities, and pretend play is very important for their development! Even better if their kitchen is close to our kitchen so they can cook their dinner while we do so too!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wooden blocks&lt;/strong&gt; are the most open-ended toys. You can build with them, create houses for your dolls, towers, tracks for yor cars, …&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dress up basket&lt;/strong&gt;. Who doesn’t like getting dressed up!? Pretending to be a ballerina, a firefighter or a cook is again a very important part of kids play. Kids learn by imagining and doing. So let them imagine and do it!!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A doll&lt;/strong&gt; to practice all this symbolic play again, taking care of a little one, like we take care of them! Feeding them, putting them to sleep, they will be busy for hours!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1440.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1440.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. KEEP TECHNOLOGY AS FAR AS POSSIBLE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids’ developing minds don’t need a flat screen in front of them to keep them entertained and still. They need to move around, jump, climb, touch, create, fall and learn how to use their bodies. &lt;strong&gt;The less screen time the more free play time&lt;/strong&gt; they will have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_8162.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_8162.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We try to use technology only in a way that is useful for us, like when kids are sick and can’t go outside, while travelling on long flights and we occasionaly do “movie night” at home, where we set the projector and watch a movie or episode together! We don’t own a TV so that also makes it easier, to not have the temtation right there. Ramona does like to watch the videos from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCWoLDKf7nJx5q1dZZbiZ_Hw/videos?view_as=subscriber&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt;, to remember our trips and experiences with family and friends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1461.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1461.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. TELL A LOT OF STORIES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1448.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1448.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading every night before sleeping is a good habit, but it doesn’t have to be the only moment we tell stories! Telling a story can be a good quiet activity to settle down after playing outside for exemple. And, we don’t always need a book to read! We should try to just &lt;strong&gt;tell stories, without picture books&lt;/strong&gt;, to allow children to create their own pictures in their mind’s eye, which is an &lt;strong&gt;essential skill for creative thinking later in life&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_2576.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_2576.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stories about their daily life activities for the youngest, fairy tales, fables, legends, and stories from history when they are older! Stories about the seasons, about nature, about festivals, … So many good ones!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1447.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1447.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Some of Ramona’s favorites!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. KEEP IMAGINATION AND ART ALIVE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making things with your hands, painting, knitting, crocheting, drawing, … it’s all a creative way to express yourself, create beautiful things, an aspect of our lifes that we should all encorage! It is &lt;strong&gt;gratifying and also good for the little hands fine motor skills&lt;/strong&gt; to explore different ways of making things! So, get your hands dirty and busy, imagine and create beautiful things!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1449.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1449.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Modeling beeswax builds strength in the hands, fine motor and artistic skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_0995.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/IMG_0995.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Watercolor painting and experiencing with the color, such a great way to encorage flexibility and imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1450.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1450.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot more behind Waldorf Education. These are just some simple ideas that hopefully you will find useful and will help your family slow down, be more present, more conected to each other and to nature.There’s are lots and lots of resorces out there! Let me know if you want to know more about and specific topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1451.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1451.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1453.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/waldorfhome/0000_IMG_1453.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Amazing seasonal guides from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wholefamilyrhythms.com/product/full-year-guide/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Whole Family Rhythms&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading me!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html">As you may know, I really like Waldorf Education. I am not a certified Waldorf teacher but I did work as an Assistant teacher at Morning Meadow and Spanish teacher at Heart Pine Waldorf school for 2 years while I lived in Gainesville, Florida. I learned a lot from amazing teachers there and it was a very revealing and uplifting period of my life! Learning about a different way of teaching, of approaching education trough a different perspective.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our Fall family rhythm</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life-scq/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our Fall family rhythm" /><published>2018-10-10T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2018-10-10T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life-scq</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life-scq/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180926_085438.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180926_085438.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been almost a month since Ramona started school after a long summer break. She started at the big kids school (how she calls it!) mid September. So &lt;strong&gt;our family rhythm&lt;/strong&gt; has switch from a late and relaxed summer schedule, that included a lot of time outside, specially in the evenings, late bed times and slow breakfasts, to a more structured and early rhythm. So, here is &lt;strong&gt;what our day to day looks like now&lt;/strong&gt;. (Very different too from our normal day in Mozambique 2 years ago! Have a look &lt;a href=&quot;http://familyonthego.life/life/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181008_085202.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181008_085202.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We wake up at 8 in the morning&lt;/strong&gt;, the latest. Ramona sleeps trough the night in her own room, but Galileo still wakes up multiple times during the night so he is still in our room. We have &lt;strong&gt;breakfast&lt;/strong&gt; together, alternating oatmeal, cereal and homemade granola, with fruit, yougurt or milk. Then I pack Ramona’s snack for school, we get dressed and out of the door by 8:50 to &lt;strong&gt;drop off Ramona at school&lt;/strong&gt;. Joe works from home most of the time but somedays he has to go to Barcelona, then he leaves at 6 am and comes back around 5 pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181005_075557.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181005_075557.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180926_080420.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180926_080420.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181001_084245.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181001_084245.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_IMG_0227.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_IMG_0227.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180921_093047.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180921_093047.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mondays I go to the &lt;strong&gt;market&lt;/strong&gt; to buy fruits and vegetables for the week, some olives and a roasted chicken that we eat for lunch. On Tuesdays and Thursdays I take a &lt;strong&gt;fitness class&lt;/strong&gt;. Galileo comes with me and plays on a mat in a corner while I sweat and get strong! On Wednesdays and Fridays I try to catch up on &lt;strong&gt;laundry and housework&lt;/strong&gt; stuff. Mid morning Galileo takes a nap. At 12 we pick up Ramona from school, which is a 5 minutes walk from home. The idea is that Ramona will stay at school for lunch and nap 2 days a week, but we are still working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181004_150624.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181004_150624.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_IMG_0810.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_IMG_0810.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We eat &lt;strong&gt;lunch&lt;/strong&gt; together around 12:20, then Ramona takes a nap from 1 to 2:30. I clean the kitchen and play with Galileo. Joe goes back to work. I wake Ramona up at 2:30 to get ready to go to school again. I walk her with Galileo in the carrier so he may fall asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180927_150845.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180927_150845.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go back home and &lt;strong&gt;while Galileo naps&lt;/strong&gt; I work on whaterver I am working at the moment (blog post, neddle felting, making granola, …). At 5 pm I pick up Ramona from school. I bring her a snack and she eats it with her friends. Then we go to the park or plaça for a while. I buy whatever I need for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180924_175637.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180924_175637.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 6:30 (it’s getting earlier by the day now because afternoons are getting shorter and it’s getting colder outside) we go home. I prepare dinner. Ramona either helps me in the kitchen or has some free play time. We eat dinner together at around 7:30-8 pm. Right after dinner starts the &lt;strong&gt;bed time routine&lt;/strong&gt;: bath, teeth, pjs, stories and bed time. Galileo and Ramona take a bath togheter. Then I take one kid and Joe takes the other to dry and put pjs on. I breastfeed Galileo to sleep and Joe tells 1,000 stories to Ramona and helps her fall asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both kids are normaly asleep by 9-9:30. Then we clean the dinner mess and we have some &lt;strong&gt;quiet time for us&lt;/strong&gt;. We either finish some work, watch a tv show or talk and plan our lives!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/20181010_112843.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/20181010_112843.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;weekends our rhythm is more relaxed&lt;/strong&gt;! We have slower mornings with pjs on and long breakfasts. We go to my avia’s house (my grandma) for lunch together with my parents, we do hikes and adventure walks, we hang out at the bar on the plaça while Ramona rides her bike around, we do things with friends, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181007_102409.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20181007_102409.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180915_135612.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/0000_20180915_135612.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sundays I do the &lt;strong&gt;meal planing&lt;/strong&gt;. I write down what we are going to have for lunch and dinner so I know what to buy on Monday. I find it very helpful so I don’t have to think every day “What am I gonna make for dinner tonight!?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/lifescq/IMG_1463.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/lifescq/IMG_1463.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like our days like this. It is true that having to rush out of the house in the morning to go to school can be a little bit stressful some days but I do think &lt;strong&gt;this rhythm is good for our family&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is yours very different to ours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to share a list of activities I have in mind to do during this season:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fall bucket list activities&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mushroom hunting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chestnut picking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nature walk with basket for colecting treasures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a fall nature table&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Knit hats for the kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake something together&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch a movie + pop corn under the blankets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake panellets (see how to make those &lt;a href=&quot;http://familyonthego.life/fall/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake apple crumble pie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make Mimi’s coconut curry pumpkin soup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a fort on a rainy day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What else should I add ??&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blackberry picking + Swimming hole + Giants = Epic weekend</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blackberry-swimming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blackberry picking + Swimming hole + Giants = Epic weekend" /><published>2018-09-13T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2018-09-13T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blackberry-swimming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blackberry-swimming/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8846.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8846.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago we had an &lt;strong&gt;unplanned amazingly fun weekend&lt;/strong&gt;. Some times the last minute plans are the best, and this time it really was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8869.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8869.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday afternoon we went on a little hike with a little basket and we picked &lt;strong&gt;1 kg of wild blackberries&lt;/strong&gt;, that later we turned out into blackberry delicious jam! Ramona was very into it! Into picking blackberries, but also into etaing them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8900.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8900.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8859.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8859.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8852.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8852.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8962.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8962.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8882.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8882.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8941.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8941.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8984.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8984.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9004.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9004.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8951.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8951.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9068.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9068.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8992.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8992.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8979.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_8979.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we went to the pool. Even if it was not so hot, we did read some magazines and chill in the hammock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9095.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9095.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9094.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9094.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Those little teeth!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9097.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9097.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we went to Santa Perpètua de Gaià, a town with a cool castle tower and church on top of a hill. Then we found this &lt;strong&gt;hidden swimming hole&lt;/strong&gt; and we swam! It was fantstic to feel the cold water and to be in the middle of nature, so disconnected but yet so close to home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9189.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9189.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9153.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9153.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9194.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9194.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9161.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9161.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9141.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9141.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9212.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9212.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9185.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9185.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday we took a day trip to &lt;strong&gt;Prades&lt;/strong&gt;, this cute red moutain town, an hour from Santa Coloma, where my aunt and uncle live! We had an amazing lunch and then in the afternoon there was a giants parade!! Ramona’s favorite!! Music, giants dancing and ice-cream, what else do you need ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9271.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9271.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9298.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9298.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9278.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9278.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9327.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9327.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9344.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;/img/blackberry/0000_IMG_9344.JPG&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is a fun video so you can see how much fun we had!! Anybody else ready for another epic rural Catalunya weekend!?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CjC23q6AJ7I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Coloma Farré</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>